

Consultant seeking roles in Software Engineering,Software Development,Application Support,Project Management,Change Management,Defect Management,Quality Management,Requirement Gathering,Core Java,Spring Boot,Cucumber,Hibernate,Maven,JDBC,JPA,Git



Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad, Mumbai Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computers]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Consultant, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Core Java, Spring

Boot, Cucumber, Hibernate, Maven, JDBC, JPA, Git

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

## Summary

5.2 years of extensive experience in Java/J2EE and ESB technologies such as Java, Micro service Spring boot, Spring Jdbc, Spring Mvc, Spring Cloud and Spring Core and Integration Platform Mule Soft ESB.

Good functional knowledge in Payment Gateways integration like Paytm, Bill Desk, Atom, Asia Pay, Pay Gate, NAB, Amex, CC Avenue, Pay Fort, Pay Maya, E Nett, Network International, Hcc, Icici, World Pay, Stripe, first data

Good experience in Micro Services using Spring Boot and Spring Boot Restful and Messaging systems like apache kafka, JMS Good experience in Persistence technologies using JDBC, JPA, Hibernate, Spring Data JPA

Good experience in Spring Security using Jsypt

Good experience in Design Patterns like Dao, DTO, Mvc, Business Delegate, Front controller and Builder and

loc,proxy,template,Interceptor and Message Facade

Good experience in Soap Web service and Restful Web service

Experience in CI/CD using Jenkins and Maven

# Work Experience

Capiot Software as Consultant Mar 2018 to Aug 2020

Payment engine (Capiot)

Role : Consultant Project :Payment engine Client : Cox & Kings Ltd.

Skills: Spring Boot JPA, Microservices, Redis, Mdm, IdVault, jsypt, Jenkins, restfulapi

Description: Cox & Kings Ltd., set up in 1758, is one of the longest established travel companies. Headquartered in India and the UK, the holiday and education travel group has subsidiaries in the United States, Canada, Japan, Singapore, Australia and New Zealand. Historically, Cox & Kings Ltd. has been an army agent, a travel agent, a printer and publisher. It has also worked as a news agent, cargo agent, ship-owner, banker, insurance agent, and dealer of several travel-related activities. Its core activities now include the sale of packaged holidays. customer need to perform payment while hotel or ticket booking. The Payment could be happen through Payment gate ways. Payment engine provides various country currencies and their respective payment gateways.

Responsibilities

Development of Micro Services using Spring boot .

Involved in Bug fixing current Micro service Development

Deployed the application on App Server using Jenkins build.

Involved in testing using Spring Junit Runner

Developed Repositories with Spring Boot JPA API to create, retrieve and update data

Involved in code review and analysis using sonar cube tool

Server Side validations using spring validator frame work

Involved in integration of all Payment gateways.

Involved in MDM integration

Involved in bug fixing and deployment.

#### Infosys as Senior Associate Consultant

Aug 2017 to Jan 2018

Role: Consultant
Project: Wave Money
Client: Cox & Kings Ltd.

Skills: Mule soft 4.0, Munit, Any point platform, Oracle Db, Kuberntees.

Description: Wave Money is an innovative way to transfer money. With Wave Money you can transfer money anywhere anytime. You can transfer money safely through your mobile phone or from one of your neighborhood Wave Shop agents. Wave Money offers you instant, safe and convenient way of sending and receiving money, bringing financial inclusion to all. Together, it will empower communities, improve people's lives, and help grow Myanmar's economy.

Responsibilities

Development of raml design.

Involved in Development of munit test cases

involved in coding and flows designs

Development of post man collection and document preparation

used database firebase connectors

involved in web service consume and exposes web services understanding the existing flows and debugging the issues

Code Merging using Git.

### Intellect Design Arena(Polaris group) as Consultant

Mar 2016 to May 2017

Role : Senior Associate Consultant

Project : HIPCUSR Client : Robert bosch

Skills: Spring Boot, JPA, Rest API, H2 Data base, Jsypt, Sonar Cube, Swagger, Mulesoft

Bosch, is a German multinational engineering and electronics company headquartered in Germany. Bosch's core products are automotive components including brakes, controls, electrical drives, electronics, fuel systems, generators, starter motors and steering systems; industrial products, such as including drives and controls, packaging technology and consumer goods; and building products, including household appliances, power tools, security systems and thermo technology. In this Project deals with service technician

,test data , master data, service Order, Top seller, clean care , Logistics, Configuration , app configuration services about product details.

#### Responsibilities:

Migrated Raml files to yaml files and Generated swagger dummy code

Involved in Understanding the existing Mule flows and converting in to spring Boot

Involved In coding in spring Boot and Unit test cases using spring Junit runner

Involved in code quality using sonar lint analysis and review Meetings with Client

Documented High level, detailed design and testing documents.

Prepared Post Man collection.

Involved in Java Coding for custom Transformers.

Involved in code check in Bit Bucket

Attending daily status calls and giving exact status to clients

Involved in connectors like spice, http, Amazon and Hybris connector.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2010

PG: M.Tech (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2013

### IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

Windows, MMC,weblogic, JNDI, JPA	
Apache Tomcat, MulServer, Eclipse, STS,	
Core Java, Servlets, Jsp, EJB , JAAS	
Oracle, Mongo Db,DB2,Postgres	
GIT,Maven,Sonar Qube	
Mule soft ESB 4	

# **Languages Known**

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

# **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time